<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<preface version="5.0" xml:id="preface" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

	<title>Preface</title>
	
	<section><title>About this book</title>
		<para>
			A primary role of a HSM is the secure management of digital keys. This 
			book introduces digital key management concepts and reinforces those concepts
			with exercises that the reader can perform on an open source Thales HSM Simulator.
		</para>
		<para>
			The reader should have a basic understanding of symmetric and asymmetric 
			cryptography.  <xref linkend="appendix_cryptography_books" /> provides a list of introductory books in cryptography
			for those wishing to learn the basics or just wanting to refresh their knowledge
			in the field of cryptography. 
		</para>
		<para>
			TODO: This book is written sequentially?  Chapters x to y (TODO) should be read in order?
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Audience</title>
		<para>
			Undergraduate and graduate students should find that this book supplements their studies 
			in the theoretical concepts of cryptography with practical applications.
		</para>
		<para>
			Software Engineers and Architects designing and building security solutions using the
			Thales brand of HSM will learn concepts and patterns of key management that can be applied
			to their designs.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Book Organisation</title>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="part-one" /> introduces digital key management concepts and provides the
			reader with practical exercises to perform on a Thales HSM Simulator.
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="introduction" /> describes the role fulfilled by a HSM. 
			The Thales series of HSM's are then introduced with a short history of their evolution.
			Finally, an open source Thales Simulator project is presented, with hands on exercises 
			for the reader to install the Simulator and then connect to it from Java, C#, and ruby clients.
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="lmk_concepts" /> covers in detail the concept of the LMKs. The knowledge gained
			in this chapter is fundamental to your understanding of the Thales HSM.  Almost all other
			chapters depend on you understanding the material covered in this chapter. This chapter concludes
			with exercise with the Thales Simulator to help instill the concepts of LMKs.
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="key_concepts" /> describes general key concepts that you need to know in addition
			to the material covered in the previous chapter about LMKs.  The knowledge in this chapter is 
			of vital importance when interacting with the Thales HSM.  Exercises are provided with the Thales
			Simulator to put the concepts learnt in this chapter into practise.
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="secure_key_exchange" /> two sites that are secured with HSMs need to have a set
			of keys that are shared between the HSMs.  This chapter describes how keys are created and shared. 
			Exercises are given to setup two demo sites with the Thales Simulator and generate and share keys
			between the demo sites.
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="dynamic_key_exchange" /> ... TODO
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="part-two" /> ... TODO ... This part takes you on a code walk through of the Thales Simulator project.
		</para>		
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Conventions</title>
		<para>TODO</para>
	</section>

<!--   <note xml:id="headsup"> -->
<!--       <title>Heads-up</title> -->
<!-- 		<para></para> -->
<!--   </note> -->
</preface>
